cf.ac.uk 2019-10-29

# Privacy - Help - Cardiff University

This privacy notice is for the Cardiff University website only (www.cardiff.ac.uk, blogs.cardiff.ac.uk, sites.cardiff.ac.uk and campaigns.cardiff.ac.uk).

For information about data protection in general and privacy notices for enquirers, students and staff, please see our [Data Protection](https://www.cardiff.ac.uk/public-information/policies-and-procedures/data-protection) pages.

## The personal data we collect

The Cardiff University website collects personal data from you in two ways:

  * data you provide yourself
  * data collected automatically.

### Data you provide yourself

Our website includes several different types of online form, as explained below. The data gathered through online forms will only be used for the purpose described on collection unless you also consent to other defined uses.

#### Online forms

When you complete an online form on www.cardiff.ac.uk, blogs.cardiff.ac.uk or sites.cardiff.ac.uk, the personal data you provide is sent to Cardiff University. It may then be passed to trusted partners under contract to help us do what you requested (such as sending you a printed prospectus).

On campaigns.cardiff.ac.uk, the data you provide may be sent to Instapage and held in accordance with the [Instapage privacy policy](https://instapage.com/privacy-policy) before being passed to Cardiff University. This data is held outside the EU and stored indefinitely unless it is deleted. To request your data or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

When you complete an online form, if you consent to receiving email marketing from us, your email address and other necessary personal data will be shared under contract with Campaign Monitor who provide us with marketing services and held in accordance with the [Campaign Monitor privacy policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies). This data may be stored outside of the EU. It is kept for as long as you choose to remain subscribed. You can unsubscribe at any time from the link provided in each email. To request your data or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

When you use our website to make an online payment, you will be sent to the Secure Trading website to enter your payment details. Data such as your name, address and card details is held in accordance with the [Secure Trading privacy policy](https://www.securetrading.com/privacy). This data may be held outside of the EU and stored for 10 years. To request your data or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

When you register to chat with a student ambassador, the data you provide is sent to Unibuddy and held in accordance with the [Unibuddy privacy policy](https://unibuddy.co/terms-and-conditions) before being shared with Cardiff University. You can delete your data by going to the Unibuddy account settings. To request the data shared with Cardiff University, or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

#### Open day booking forms

Our Open Day booking forms are hosted on Eventbrite. When you book, data will be sent to Eventbrite and held in accordance with the [Eventbrite privacy policy](https://www.eventbrite.com/privacypolicy) before being sent to Cardiff University. It may be held outside of the EU but Eventbrite is certified compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield. The data is stored for as long as you use the Eventbrite service. To request or delete your Eventbrite data, contact [privacy@eventbrite.com](mailto:privacy@eventbrite.com)

#### Feedback

On some parts of our website we use Hotjar to gather feedback. If you provide your email address it will be stored within the EU in accordance with the [Hotjar privacy policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) and kept for 365 days. With your consent, Hotjar will associate website activity data with your email address and also store data about your country, device and browser and language setting. To request this data, withdraw consent or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

#### Live chat

If you use our live chat, the data you give us (such as your name, email address and the contents of your chat session) will be sent to LiveChat and stored in accordance with the [LiveChat privacy policy](https://www.livechatinc.com/privacy-policy). This data may be stored outside of the EU but LiveChat is certified compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield. The data is held indefinitely but you can request it or ask for it to be deleted by contacting [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk).

### Data collected automatically

The data collected automatically by our website helps us understand which parts of it are most popular, where visitors are coming from and how they are using it. This allows us to make improvements in future.

#### Usage statistics

As you use our website, data about the pages visited is sent to Google Analytics so that we know how many people are using it. This includes the individual pages visited, an anonymised IP address, the device, browser and the website you came from. Google can also collect demographic and interests information from the DoubleClick cookie, if it's present on your device.

Data may be held outside of the EU but Google is certified compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield. The data is stored for 26 months in accordance with [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy). To request this data or ask for it to be deleted contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

#### Advertising effectiveness

On parts of our website, we use code provided by Google, Facebook, Twitter or Snapchat to serve adverts based on someone’s past visit (retargeting) and to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns. This code sends data to Google, Facebook or Snapchat about the individual pages visited, actions completed on the page, IP address, device and browser.

This data may be held outside of the EU. Google, Facebook, Twitter and Snapchat are certified compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield. You can request this data or ask for it to be deleted via the [Facebook Your Information](https://www.facebook.com/your_information), [Google’s Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/), [Twitter privacy controls](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads) and [Snapchat Support](https://support.snapchat.com/en-US/a/privacy-settings2 "Snapchat Support") pages or visit [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) and switch off behavioural advertising from a large number of companies.

We may also use code provided by Infinity to determine whether online adverts result in clicks on the phone numbers displayed on our website. The code sends data to Infinity about the pages visited and the phone number clicked as well as IP address, a generated Infinity visitor ID, device screen resolution, browser information and Google Analytics ID number. The data is held in the UK. Page view data is stored for three months and other data is stored until the contract with Infinity comes to an end. To request this data or ask for it to be deleted contact [legal@infinity.co](mailto:legal@infinity.co)

We may also use code provided by Adform to measure the effectiveness of other online adverts. No personal data is sent to Adform.

#### YouTube videos

On pages containing YouTube videos, data about the videos you watch will be sent to Google and stored in accordance with [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy). It may be used by Google to personalise advertising for you. You can opt out via [Google’s Ads Settings](https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated) and request or delete your data via your [Google Account](https://myaccount.google.com/).

#### Interactive maps

The maps on the Cardiff University website use the Google Maps API in accordance with [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy). By using these maps you agree to be bound by the [Google Maps/Google Earth additional terms of service](https://maps.google.com/help/terms_maps.html).

When we use interactive maps that show your position, we will do so only with your consent. If you provide consent, the map will use the coordinates of your current location but this data will not be sent to us or stored.

#### Interactive charts

On pages of our website that include interactive charts, data including your IP address, browser and device is sent to ChartBlocks and held on Amazon Web Services storage for three years in accordance with the [ChartBlocks privacy policy](https://www.chartblocks.com/en/about/privacy-policy). The data may be held outside of the EU but Amazon is certified compliant with the EU-US Privacy Shield. To request this data or ask for it to be deleted, contact [web@cardiff.ac.uk.](mailto:web@cardiff.ac.uk)

#### SoundCloud audio

Where we use embedded audio, information about the page you visited and what you listen to will be sent to SoundCloud and held in accordance with the [SoundCloud privacy policy](https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy). You can request your data or ask for it to be deleted via the [SoundCloud Help Center](https://help.soundcloud.com/hc/en-us/sections/115001107587-Privacy).

#### Email marketing

When you consent to receiving email from us and you click the links in an email we sent you information such as your IP address, the email software you are using and the links you clicked will be sent to Campaign Monitor and stored in accordance with the [Campaign Monitor privacy policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/). The data may be held outside of the EU. Collecting this data helps us understand what email content is most popular so that we can send more relevant emails to you in future. It is held for as long as you remain subscribed. You can unsubscribe at any time from the link provided in each email.

#### User behaviour

On some parts of our website we use Hotjar to record anonymous data about how specific pages are used (such as clicks or mouse movements). This does not collect or store any personal data.

#### Twitter feeds

On pages that have embedded Twitter content, we instruct Twitter not to record any information about you. You can opt-out of all Twitter tracking from the [Twitter Personalisation](https://twitter.com/personalization) settings page.

#### Website performance

On some parts of our website we use Catchpoint to record how long pages take to load. This is so that we can learn how to make it faster. No personal data is sent to Catchpoint but it does record the browser used on the pages we are monitoring.

#### Approximate location

Our website detects the country you are in, based on your IP address. This allows us to personalise parts of our website for international visitors.

#### Server logs

Our web servers record requests for web pages (URLs) but no personal data is collected or stored.

## Do not track

Our website does not currently support the “Do not track” browser setting.

## Changes to this privacy notice

We reserve the right to change this information without notice.
